# Ronan Lewsley

## **Software Engineer**

23 Oakvale Gardens, Dunmurry, BT17 OSD

07894714510 ronanlewsley99@gmail.com

Skills

I am an experienced agile practitioner, working mainly within the scrumban methodology. I exude passion and dedication to all things tech, always wanting to learn more, and never limiting myself to one framework or language, as I have found all to have their place in the right scenario. Passionate about Kubernetes, and the ability to scale that it has brought to devops. I am keenly interested in developing my skills in regards to Continuous integration/ deployment pipelines, becoming familiar with more complex workflows to create smooth automated testing and deployments.

**Experience** 

## **Veriteer** / Full stack engineer

May 2022 - Present, Belfast

At Veriteer, I work as a full stack engineer, doing everything from Frontend to web server configuration and dev-ops/ deployment.

Utilised Mac OS, as a company standard. As a team we have been developing a proof of concept E-commerce platform to prove a new opportunity viable to the market. The basis of this is a PHP E-commerce system called Spryker with a loaded stack to allow for fast scalable e-commerce platforms for the largest businesses around the world.

Stack utilised a Vue JS SPA frontend to display the store, with the Spryker stack running in behind. Working with Spryker has afforded me opportunities to work with, understand and deploy a multitude of services, i.e. redis, jenkins & elasticsearch.

Worked on deployment using Spryker custom Docker interpretation to AWS EC2 instance, with GitHub Actions running the CI/CD pipelines. Currently studying toward CKA (certified Kubernetes Administrator) with the Linux foundation

### Flax & Teal / Junior full stack developer

June 2020 - April 2022, Belfast

At Flax & Teal I worked primarily as a Full Stack Web developer. This was extended slightly to working on data engineering and Infrastructure/ DevOps tasks.

Utilised Ubuntu/ Debian throughout my work here, as it was a company wide policy. Many of the projects I worked on were open-source, as progressing open-source ideas and technologies were a primary objective for the company. Efficient utilising Bash as a consequence to Linux experience.

Main stacks worked on consisted of PHP Laravel backends, with a frontend VueJS SPA. The main database I worked with was PostgreSQL, but also had experience with noSQL solutions such as Apache Cassandra.

Worked on a structural monitoring project that integrated raw sensor information that was aggregated on a self-hosted instance of open-source platform Thingsboard. Data was then extracted from this platform utilising their API to provide a more user-friendly approach to some of the analytics on a custom web interface that I initially created.

Developed a natural disaster simulating geo-spatial solution, that had been in development from before my employment. Most notably making changes to the simulation interface to modernise and improve its usability. This afforded experience of working with PostGIS.

Leveraging the OpenFAAS library with Python and Kubernetes as a deployment mechanism, I created and deployed various serverless functions as analytics tools to create useful metrics from data being tracked on Thingsboard.

Worked with Helm as a deployment tool for templating Kubernetes, making deployments more manageable and intuitive. This led to infrastructure testing utilising Helm tests for liveness checking of key services and testing any external dependencies such as credential checking before services start.

Using the Grafana/ Loki/ Prometheus stack, from Grafana Labs, began gathering metrics from services and pods across the cluster, for monitoring of resources, errors, and request times. These metrics could be shown graphically using tools within Grafana. Metrics would be extracted from both the Loki log aggregator and Prometheus' time-series database. This would also allow for automated alerts on issues arising within the cluster, to be forwarded to webhooks such as a Microsoft Teams Channel.

#### Education

# **Ulster University Jordanstown** / BSc Hons in Computing Science

Sep 2018 - June 2022, Belfast

Studied a large variety of computing topics, namely cloud technologies, artificial intelligence and full stack deployment. Created a full stack social blogging platform that utilised Natural language processing to assign topics to posts, for easier searching

# **Belfast Metropolitan College** / Access Foundation Diploma in Maths & Computing

September 2017 - June 2018, Belfast

Studied all branches of advanced Mathematics including; statistics, mechanics and pure math. Also studied foundational computing systems and database design.

### **Awards**

Certified Spryker foundations developer by Spryker GMBH 2022 Certified Customer Experience fundamentals by MadeFor 2022